scrooge.co.uk 2019-06-12

# Privacy Policy | Scrooge.co.uk

At Scrooge we want you to know about and have control over the data you share with us and how we process them. This text, which we call our _Privacy Policy_ , explains in a concise way what kind of data we collect and how we use them. Its aim is to help you make informed choices regarding the kind of data you share with us. 

  * ###  Scrooge & Personal Data at a glance 

We encourage you to thoroughly read this Policy, however here is a short summary of the key points for your convenience: 

    * When you use Scrooge — even for a simple product search — we receive non-identifying information about you, like your IP address or your device type. Furthermore, by choosing to create a Scrooge account you share your e-mail address, your cellphone number and other elements of a public profile — such as a profile picture — with us. 

We use this information to keep your account secure and to contact you about matters relating to your account. 

    * Scrooge aims at improving your e-commerce experience. When using your account, you can save products you own or just purchased or products you are merely interested in. We use this information, along with your searches, to show you personalized search results and to notify you about outstanding offers you might be interested in. 
    * Scrooge is also a platform for public communications: shop and product reviews and discussions are public and visible to anyone visiting Scrooge, along with the author's username and profile picture. 

When you post a shop or product review, we may ask you for a proof of purchase — which we will not publish — in order to verify the review. 

    * You can use your account settings to choose what data you share with us and to adjust your communication preferences. 
    * You can request deletion of your account data at any time by sending an e-mail to [dpo@scrooge.co.uk](mailto:dpo@scrooge.co.uk) from the e-mail address associated with your account. 

Feel free to contact us at [privacy@scrooge.co.uk](mailto:privacy@scrooge.co.uk) for any questions or remarks regarding this Policy. 

## Data you share with us

Some of our services require additional data to operate. For instance, you need a Scrooge account to save products into. We collect the following data you choose to share with us and use it to operate our services. 

  * ### Account information

You don't need to register to use Scrooge, however you can choose to do so in order to use some of our additional services, such as our "Favourites" system, or to write a product review. When doing so, we will ask for your e-mail address and a username of your choice. The username will be visible along with your public activity, such as discussions and shop or product reviews. We will use your e-mail to reach out for you and to send notifications. You can adjust your notification options using your preferences. 

We may ask for your cellphone number in order to verify your account. We will never publish this number. 

Finally, you can choose to share some optional information with us, such as your age or sex, to help us understand our user base better. 

  * ### Data you publish

You may choose to publish information through Scrooge, either in the form of a shop or product review, or through our discussions platform. This information will be available to Scrooge visitors, as well as visitors of affiliate pages that embed Scrooge content. 

  * ### Location

You may choose to share a location with us to help you choose the suitable product or shop, by e.g. calculating postage. This location need not be accurate and will not be used for any other purpose. 

  * ### Products and Purchases

You may choose to save your favourite products in your account. We may kindly ask you to write a review for some of the products you own, or notify you about changes you may be interested in. You can manage your favourites and change you notification settings at any time. 

## Data we receive about you

When you use our services or visit affiliate sites that embed Scrooge content, we may receive information about you. We use this information — along with information you share with us — to operate our services. 

  * ### Cookies

Cookies are small text snippets containing data that are stored at your computer or mobile device and sent back every time you visit us. We use cookies to offer personalized content, to measure our service performance and to gather statistical data about our services' usage. Most browsers will accept cookies automatically, however you can adapt your browser's behaviour through its settings. Keep in mind however that cookies are required for your Scrooge account to work, although they are not strictly necessary for all uses: for instance, merely searching for a product will work without cookies. Learn more about cookies at Scrooge. 

  * ### Browsing Activity

All internet services have access to information sent by your device while using them. In our case, we receive data when you browse Scrooge and when you interact with the rest of our services, even if you are not logged in. This includes, for instance, when you visit a page at Scrooge, when you see a product through our mobile app or when you visit an affiliate site that embeds our content. We call this data set your Browsing Activity. 

Your Browsing Activity contains information such as your IP address, your device's type and make, your browser and operating system version, the page you are visiting, the page that referred you to us, the search terms you use and your cookies. 

We use this information to make sure our services operate in a secure and fast manner, to improve the content we display and to assess Scrooge's efficiency. We may also use this information, along with data you share with us, to display personalized content that may be closer to your interests. 

## Information we share with others

Scrooge is build to improve your e-commerce experience. In general we don't share your personal data with anyone. When we do, we will do so with your consent, or because it is necessary in order to operate our services, or to comply with the law. 

  * ### Sister companies

We may share your personal data with any of our sister companies, always respecting this Policy. 

  * ### Service Provicers

We use third-party services in order to operate our own services. We receive services from a number of companies in the EU and the USA. For instance, we are using Google Analytics and Inspectlet to help us better understand how are users use our services. We also use third-party data networks to connect our infrastructure to the internet. We may share data related to your use of Scrooge with some of these service providers, always complying with this Policy and only under the provision that the data will be used only pursuant to our instructions. 

We also share your payment card data with payment service providers in order to complete financial transactions or to facilitate a dispute. 

In order to secure your data, we are using strong encryption throughout our site. 

  * ### Advertisements

Some of our pages include 3rd-party content from Google Ads. When you view these pages, Google may receive information about you. For more information, please see the [Google Ads Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

  * ### Law

We may store, use or share your personal data if we deem that this is required in order to comply with the law, or a legal process or governmental request; to protect the safety of any person; to protect the integrity of our service against spam or abuse; to address fraud. 

  * ### Legal Status

The data you share with us remains in possession of our company. You can request deletion or modification at any time by e-mail at [dpo@scrooge.co.uk](mailto:dpo@scrooge.co.uk). 

  * ### Non-personalised information

We share non-personalised information such as statistical or aggregate data about popular products, shops or product categories with the shops listed in Scrooge. We also share data such as the total visitors redirected to each shop and the total clicks our advertisement campaigns received, without sharing any identifying data. 

## Manage your data

You can access, amend and/or delete your data at any time through your user profile page. You can also request deletion of your account. Furthermore you can choose to be excluded from certain types of processing. 

  * ### Accessing and amending personal data

If you are a registered user, you can access, amend and/or delete your personal data through your profile page at any time. 

  * ### Deletion

You can request deletion of your account by sending an e-mail to [dpo@scrooge.co.uk](mailto:dpo@scrooge.co.uk). For administrative and technical reasons, your Browsing Activity will be retained for up to 60 days after your account has been deleted. 

  * ### Objection to processing

You can use your account settings to exclude your data from certain types of processing. For instance, you can disable notifications. 

  * ### Additional help and information

Feel free to contact us for any question or remark regarding this Privacy Policy. 

The data controller responsible for your personal data is: 

Skroutz S.A.  
Ref: Data Protection Officer  
Alekou Panagouli 91, Nea Ionia, 142 34 Greece 

If you wish to raise a concern about our use of your information (and without prejudice to any other rights you may have), you have the right to do so with your local supervisory authority or with Skroutz's lead supervisory authority, the Greek Data Protection Authority. You can find their contact details [here](http://www.dpa.gr/portal/page?_pageid=33,43534&_dad=portal&_schema=PORTAL). 

## Children and Scrooge

Scrooge's services are not directed to children. You must be at least 16 to use our services. 

## Changes to this policy

We may update this Policy from time to time, however the most recent version will always be available at https://www.scrooge.co.uk/privacy. 

If we deem an update important enough, we will notify you via e-mail using the address associated with your account, if any. 

By using our services you accept this Policy and are bound by its terms. 

This Policy was last updated on May 24, 2018 and is effective May 25, 2018.
